

Dan Nguyen Gia Laravel/WordPress Developer

+84 916681139 danhoat@gmail.com

♀ 523 Do Xuan Hop, P. Phuoc Long B, Ho Chi Minh City

Languages

English

VietNam

Social

Linkedin
linkedin.com/dannguyengia

Github github.com/danngyw

PROFILE

Around 9+ years of experience as a PHP Web Application Developer, specializing in by developing WordPress themes, plugins and payment API. Extensive experience in payment API work and how to implement it. Experience in technical support of and can handle almost WordPress, PHP and Hosting popular issues.

I have in-depth knowledge of website systems/technology, how to build and how it works.

WORK EXPERIENCE

PHP Developer at JVIT - Ho Chi Minh City

Apr 2023 - Jun 2024

JV-IT is a company specializing in outsourcing for the Japanese market. Customize WordPress Project,Laravel and Simphony for Japan market Build local system by using Docker or work directly on the AWS system

Fullstack Developer

Jun 2022 - May 2023

Work as a freelancer. Almost job relates to customize WordPress site such as customize layout/function/workflow of the theme, implement payment gateway.

Senior WordPress Developer at EngineThemes - Ho Chi Minh City

Jun 2013 - Aug 2022

EngineThemes is a WordPress application theme creator.

- Converting HTML Templates into Fully functional WordPress themes.
- Implement payment gateway for WordPress themes and plugins.
- Technical support work directly with customers via email to help them solve problems.
- Offer Customization services for client
- Fix bugs and maintenance themes/plugins.
- Conduct internal training for developers within the team.

Tools and technologies: WordPress, XML, HTML/CSS, PHP & MYSQL, jQuery, Ajax,Sublime,Photoshop, Bootstraps, Sass.

Key achievement: FreelanceEngine theme, MicrojobEngine theme.

PHP/WordPress Developer at Goscom - Ho Chi Minh City

Jun 2012 - May 2013

Goscom is a software outsourcing company.

- Experience with Xampp (Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP, HTML/CSS).
- Convert PSD file to HTML/CSS template.
- Customize PHP WordPress/Woocommerce and support customers.

EDUCATION

HCMUS - Bachelor's degree - Ho Chi Minh City

Sep 2006 - Jun 2011

Learn programming languages like C/C++/C#/JAVA/ASP.NET and OPP, MVC, algorithms ... Develop simple applications.

SKILLS

- Excellent ability to troubleshoot and work with clients to solve problems or find solutions to requests.
- Proficiency in OOP with a good understanding of MVC practices.
- Strong knowledge of RESTful Web Services and JSON.
- Excellent PHP & MySQL, JavaScript, Bootstraps and Sass.
- Good to debug and solve PHP/WordPress problems.

- Experience implementing payment gateway/escrow API(PayPal/Stripe...).
- In-depth understanding of eCommerce systems, application implementation.

STRENGTHS

- Online Comunication Effective online communication, present compelling messages in a one-way setting in order to be successful.
- Time Managment Prioritize my tasks and efficiently organize everything to achieve my goals

ENVIRONMENT

WordPress, PHP MySQL, Git, Github, Docker, Vuejs, cPanel/FTP Hosting, Firebase, Bootstrap Framework, PSD, HTML/CSS/JS, SCSS/SASS, Woocommerce, XAMPP/MAMPP